《绿箭》前情提要
Previously, on "Arrow..."
但有些事情永远不能提起
But there are some things that must never be spoken of.
你怎能不告诉我  马尔科姆·梅林是我父亲
How could you not tell me Malcolm Merlyn was my father?!
莎拉  你不是个杀手
Sara, you're not a killer!
我该是什么就是什么
I am what I need to be.
罗伊  你是个危险的人
Roy, you're dangerous.
有些人就是扭曲
Some people are just broken, man.
我不会让罗伊遇上发生在斯莱德身上的事
I am not letting what happened to Slade happen to Roy.
那是我想的东西吗
Is that what I think it is?
米拉库鲁  我们要用它制造解药
Mirakuru. We're going to use it to make a cure.
没有改变吗
No change?
没有
Nope.
好多血和好多米拉库鲁混在一起
So much blood mixed in with so much Mirakuru,
我不知道那是好事还是坏事
I don't know if it's good or bad.
我们真的很需要解药
We could really use that cure.
我今早和凯特琳聊过了
I talked to Caitlin this morning.
他们在努力
They're working on it.
没提到伊莎贝尔·罗切夫的死吗
No mention on Isabel Rochev's death?
完全没有  我也没指望有华丽的讣告
Not a thing. I wasn't expecting a glowing obituary,
但她是失踪一周的福布斯500强总裁
but she's a Fortune 500 CEO that's been missing for a week now.
我还以为她会占点篇幅呢
You'd think she'd have some column inches.
他躺在那我觉得有些害怕
Does the fact that him lying there freaks me out a little
这说明我是个坏人吗
make me a bad person?
费利西蒂  我觉得世界上没有什么力量
Felicity, I don't think there's a force on earth
能让你变成坏人
that can make you a bad person.
但我饿坏了
But I am starving.
一起吃晚餐吗
Dinner?
好
Yeah.
但是不去大贝利[大肚]汉堡店
No Big Belly burger, though.
会让我肚子变大
It's giving me a big belly.
那就吃寿司
Sushi, then.
你都昏迷了怎么还能吓我...
How can you be unconscious and freak me out at the same...
一跳啊
time?
罗伊
Roy?
天啊
Oh, my God!
你吓坏我了
Oh, you scared me.
罗伊
Roy?
忘记拿手机了
Forgot my phone.
罗伊  听着
Roy, listen--
狄格
Dig!
-你没事吧  -快去
- You ok? - Go!
罗伊
Roy!
怎么回事
What's going on?
让开  让开  让开
Move, move, move, move, move, move, move, move!
让开
Move, move!
绿箭  第二季第二十集
你觉得罗伊没事吧
You think Roy's ok?
别告诉我你现在在想罗伊的事
Please tell me that you're not thinking about Roy right now.
我们终于独处了  躺在
We're finally alone, in bed,
一家豪华酒店房间里的床上
in a very nice hotel room.
你付不起这豪华酒店的房费
A hotel room that you couldn't afford.
我和这里的经理有点关系
I have something of a history with the manager.
我还真是想不到啊
I can only imagine.
我想我有次就是倒的这间房里的垃圾
I think I trashed this specific room once.
但是特权用完了
But favors run out.
我们该考虑找一个更长久的地方
We should think about getting a more permanent place.
我们
We?
你和劳蕾尔住一起可能也腻了
Well, you're probably getting tired of staying with Laurel,
既然罗伊在铸造厂
and we can't sleep in the foundry
我们也不能睡在那里  所以...
now that Roy's there, so...
不过  我是说"我们"
But, I mean, "We,"
你这是让我搬去和你同居吗
now you're asking me to move in with you?
你的手机响了
Hey, your phone's ringing.
我知道
I know.
好吧  我俩的手机都在响
Okay, both our phones are ringing,
这从来不是好事
that's never good.
费利西蒂  来电
出什么事了
What happened?
我不知道  前一分钟他还昏迷不醒
I don't know. One minute he's comatose,
接下来他就掀翻了电脑设备
the next, he's flipping over computer equipment.
他比斯莱德在你家还失控
He was a lot more out of control than Slade was at your house.
他看起来像罗伊  但他不是罗伊
He looked like Roy, but he...wasn't Roy.
你觉得他要去哪里
Where do you think he's headed?
我不知道  但我们得找到他
I don't know, but we have to find him.
出乎大家意料之外
Despite everyone's predictions,
你在最近的投票中超过了塞巴斯蒂安·布拉德
you've managed to pull ahead of Sebastian Blood in recent polls.
是的  我们所传达的信息和选民产生了共鸣
Yes. I think our message is resonating with the voters.
星城人民知道我高瞻远瞩
The people of Starling know that I have a vision,
并拥有经验丰富的机构  能让梦想成真
and the experienced apparatus to make that vision a reality.
你觉得人民该给你  而不是布拉德议员
What would you say is the main reason
投票的主要原因是什么
they should vote for you over Alderman Blood?
这个嘛
Well, um...
布拉德议员没有孩子
Alderman Blood isn't a parent.
作为父母的重点
And the soul of being a parent
就是保证孩子拥有美好的未来
is making sure that your children have a bright future.
我很幸运  我为我的孩子安排了美好的未来
And I've been very lucky to be able to do that for my own.
是啊  年度最佳母亲
Yeah. Mother of the year.
我正在接受采访呢
Uh, we're in the middle of an interview.
那我长话短说
Oh, I'll keep it short.
你不能在威登酒吧召开集会
You can't have your rally at Verdant.
这是我唯一拥有的未被你荼毒的地方
It's the only place I have that hasn't been poisoned by you.
能让我们聊会儿吗
Can you give me one moment, please?
关掉
Turn it off.
西娅  我知道你很生气
Thea, I know you're upset,
你有理由如此
and you have every right to be,
但我们得去别的地方聊
but we need to talk somewhere else.
我不想跟你聊了  我只是过来告诉你
I'm done talking. I just came by to tell you,
你想用我的酒吧是绝对不可能的事
it'll be a cold day in hell before you can use my club.
我们不能集会前一天突然改变地点
We can't just change the venue the day before.
我肯定你能想出办法的
I'm sure you can figure something else.
毕竟  你拥有经验丰富的机构
I mean, you have such an experienced apparatus.
你签了合同
You signed a contract.
我还以为你的下限不会更低了呢...
Just when I thought you couldn't go any lower...
你竟然威胁你自己的女儿
You threaten your own daughter.
莫伊拉
Moira.
怎么回事
What's going on?
抱歉让你看到这些
Sorry you had to witness that.
她被绑架后
After her abduction,
我还以为你俩应该更为亲密
I'd think that the two of you would be closer than ever.
情况很复杂
It's a very complicated situation.
我的建议是
Well, my advice?
简化它
Simplify it.
你要么做个母亲  要么做候选人
You have to be either a mother or a candidate.
没法两全其美
You can't be both.
现在不行  你不能分散注意
Not right now. You cannot split your focus.
你说得太对了
You're absolutely right.
你无精打采时真可爱
You're really cute when you're mopey.
我不是无精打采
I'm not mopey.
无精打采是你的默认状态  奥利
Mopey's your default, Ollie.
这是你郁积魅力的一部分
It's part of your smoldering charm.
我的确有郁积魅力
I do have smoldering charm.
但你比平常更加无精打采
But you're more than usual mopey.
一切都还好吗
Is everything all right?
没事
It's fine.
奥利
Ollie.
我和汤米出去玩
Tommy had me out a little bit later
回来的有些晚了
than maybe I should have been, and...
所以我有点累了
I'm wiped.
你想让我走吗
Well, you want me to go?
我答应过莎拉要给她辅导三角学的
I promised Sara I'd help her with her trigonometry.
那是什么东西
I don't know what that is.
你很可爱
You are very cute.
睡一会儿吧
Get some sleep.
再见
Bye.
晚安  奎恩夫人
Good night, Mrs. Queen.
晚安
Good night.
你昨晚没和汤米一起出去
You didn't go out with Tommy last night.
谢谢你偷听我的整个谈话  妈妈
Thanks for eavesdropping on my entire conversation, Mom.
真好
That's--that's nice.
宝贝  你有烦心事
Sweetheart, something's bothering you,
和我说说
tell me what it is.
爸爸会杀了我的
Dad's going to kill me.
你父亲是爱你的
Your father loves you.
我爱你
I love you.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
很糟糕
It's bad.
怎么回事
What happened?
我让一个女孩怀孕了
I got a girl pregnant.
劳蕾尔怀孕了
Laurel's pregnant?
没有
No.
不是劳蕾尔
Not Laurel.
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
我们不能就这么到处瞎逛
We can't just ride around all night
指望能找到他
hoping to lay eyes on him.
-狄格尔  -他不在住处
- Diggle? - His place is clean.
我认为他不会回去
I don't think he's been back here.
有个电话召急救车去14大街和霍巴特路路口
Call just went out for an ambulance at 14th and Hobart.
有四个人遭到一个
There's four men seriously assaulted...
14大街与霍巴特路路口
穿红色兜帽衫人的袭击
by someone wearing a red hoodie.
发生了什么
What happened?
那家伙突然冒出来  直接就来打我们
Guy jumped us. Came out of nowhere.
那家伙跟打了鸡血一样
The dude is 'roided out or something.
疯狂得很
Crazy like.
再会  辛
See ya, Sin.
再见[西语]
Adios.
小屁孩
Yo, Abercrombie.
等等  你去哪了
Hold up. Where you been, man?
我去找过你差不多20次了
I went over to your place like 20 times.
西娅说你去外地了
Thea said you skipped town.
我去
Holy crap.
你打架了吗
Have you been in a fight?
辛  这家伙在找你麻烦吗
Sin, is this guy bothering you?
不  他很冷静  真的  你走开吧
No, no, no, he's chill. Seriously, just step off.
有什么问题吗
We going to have a problem, guy?
你真要这么着吗
Seriously?
别管他  他没事
Just leave him alone, he's fine.
怎么  怂了不说话了
Oh, what, you got nothing smart to say?
费利西正在蒂通过遍布全城的
Felicity's running facial recognition
监控摄像头进行面部识别
on traffic cameras throughout the city.
也许永远都完不成
Which could take forever.
在罗伊伤害其他人之前我们必须把他打倒
We need to take Roy down now before he attacks any more people.
"我不想见到你这句话"
What part of "I want nothing to do with you"
哪个字你听不懂
are just not understanding?
我是来找莎拉的
I came by to see Sara.
那他呢
And what about him?
他在跟踪我
He's been stalking me.
他在保护你
He's protecting you.
因为什么呢
From what?
斯莱德·威尔逊还没被抓到
Slade Wilson is still at large.
他已经尝试过伤害你了
He already tried hurting you once.
他没有伤到我
He didn't hurt me.
他告诉了我真相  你认为是坏事的真相
He told me the truth, which I know you think is a bad thing,
其实不是坏事
but it's actually not.
如果意味着我要失去你那就是
It is if it costs me you.
你的谎言才是
Your lies did that.
现在  我要去楼上的储藏室
Now, I'm going to go upstairs to the stock room,
如果有人拿小酒杯打我
and if I get attacked by some shot glasses,
我自己会报警的
I'll call 911.
谢谢你照顾她
Thanks for taking care of her.
幸运的是  她不像你那么善于消失
Lucky for me, she's not as good at disappearing as you were.
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
你见到西娅了吗
Have you seen Thea?
你眼睛怎么了
What happened to your eye?
没什么  化个妆掩盖一下就好
It's ok. I could cover it with make-up.
如果我有那手艺的话
If I work make-up.
没事的
It's fine.
谁干的
Who did this to you?
说来话长
It's a long story.
我问你是谁干的
I asked you who.
罗伊
Roy.
他现在脑子不正常
But he's not right in the head.
他被人注射了什么东西
He got injected with something.
也许是药吧  但那让他变得很强壮
A drug, I don't know, but it made him strong.
就像  漫画里的英雄那样
Like, comic book strong.
我知道那听上去很疯狂
Look, I know it sounds nuts--
其实不会
It really doesn't.
莎拉  罗伊是个朋友
Sara, Roy's a friend.
他需要帮助  而不是被打
He needs help, not a beat down.
我等会给你回电话
I'll have to call you right back.
我需要留下吗  布拉德先生
Do you want me to stay, Mr. Blood?
不用  谢谢你
No, thank you.
没事的
I'll be fine.
我的新保镖
My new body man.
他有点担心过头
He's a little over-protective.
-请坐  -不用  谢谢
- Please. - No, thank you.
不得不说你的来访有点突然
I'd say this visit is unexpected,
但我会有什么说什么
but I despise understatements.
我要退出竞选了
I'm dropping out of the race.
我会在今晚的集会上发布败选演说
I'm making a concession speech at my rally tonight.
上一轮投票后你是领先的
You're ahead in the latest polls.
即便是持最怀疑态度的专家
Even the most skeptical pundits
都说你很可能胜出
are saying you could actually pull this out.
我是出于礼貌才当面告诉你这事的
I felt I owed you the courtesy of informing you in person.
但我不需要向你解释什么
I don't, however, owe you an explanation as well.
是的  你说得对
No, you don't.
但是我希望你解释一下
But I'd appreciate one.
无论你是要做什么事  莫伊拉
What you're doing, Moira,
只要会给我带来好处
as much as it benefits me,
似乎都不合常理
doesn't really make much sense.
是为了我的女儿
It's my daughter.
这个时候  她比星城更需要我
At the moment, she needs me more than Starling does.
你做了正确的事
Well, you're doing the right thing.
我要改变这座城市  莫伊拉
I'm going to change this city, Moira.
新的时代即将开启
A new day is coming.
一个更好的时代
A better day.
对我们所有人
For all of us.
我知道有些事情让人丧气  宝贝
I know things seem bleak, sweetheart,
但我们会解决的  我保证
but we're going to figure this out, I promise.
妈妈  这公平吗
Mom, does it seem fair?
犯了
To make...
一个错误  那感觉
one mistake, and it...
就好像我的整个生命已经结束了
feels like my entire life is over.
你的生活才没有完蛋
Oh, your life is far from over.
你确定孩子是你的吗
Are you sure it's yours?
只要你有钱  奥利弗
Where there is money, Oliver,
就会有人想来占你的便宜
there are people looking to take advantage.
她不是那种人  她是个好人  妈妈
She's not that type of person. She's a good person, Mom.
她是...
She's...
好吧
All right.
我不知道该怎么办  我该怎么办呢
I don't know what to do. What do I do?
人非圣贤孰能无错  奥利弗  我希望
We all make mistakes, Oliver. And I had hoped
有天你也会原谅我所犯下的错误
that one day you'd forgive me for any that I might make, so...
好了  我出去下
All right, um, I'll be right back.
辛在威登酒吧  14街和霍巴特街路口
Verdant, 14th and Hobart,
还有另一个酒吧都有看到他
and the bar Sin spotted him at.
-他好像正往东走  -东边有什么
- He looks to be moving east. - What's east?
奎恩家的豪宅
Queen mansion.
如果他还记得西娅的住处
If he still remembers where Thea lives--
以前的住处
well, used to live,
但罗伊并不知道...
but Roy doesn't know that...
或许他的人性并没有完全泯灭
There might be something in Roy still left in there.
或许他只是碰巧往东走而已
Or it's just a coincidence that he's moving east.
我知道这件事牵扯到了辛
Ahem. I know that Sin's involved,
但不要让它影响你的判断
but don't let that cloud your judgment.
别忘了以前罗伊可是经常影响你的判断
Well, don't let the fact that this used to be Roy cloud yours.
辛
Sin.
我找到罗伊了
I found Roy.
我跟你说了回家去
Well, I thought I told you to go home.
是的  我就在家这儿呢
Yeah, that's where I am right now.
还有他
And so is he.
罗伊
Roy!
他不在这儿
He's not here.
我是奥利弗
It's Oliver.
是我啊
It's me.
你现在之所以这样
What you're doing right now,
全都是因为米拉库鲁
it's because of the Mirakuru.
你是个好人  罗伊
You're a good person, Roy.
你的良知和灵魂还在
You have a conscience and a soul.
利用这些来顽强抗争  你能做到的
I need you to use those and fight this. You can do it!
把箭放下  放下
Drop the arrow, drop it!
不要
No!
今晚满月
A full moon tonight.
所以稀奇古怪的事更可能发生
That really brings out the whack jobs.
好消息是不可能会有更怪的事发生了
Good news is, it can't get any stranger.
我的朋友需要你的帮助
My friend needs your help.
看来我错了  我再打给你
I was wrong. Got to call you back.
有些是旧伤复发
Some of this damage is chronic.
我猜是从屋顶上跳下来而引发的
The cost of jumping off rooftops, I guess.
我要赶快恢复
I need to get back on my feet.
我可以给你个支架
I can give you a brace,
但你走起路来还是会很痛
but you'll still be in horrendous amounts of pain.
六个月前  这个药柜面临清空的危险
Six months ago, this cabinet would have been empty.
华人三合会想阻碍我们的药品运输船
The Chinese Triad was stopping all of our med shipments--
后来有个人阻止了他们
until someone stopped them.
从那之后  我一直想找个机会谢谢你
Ever since, I've been looking for a way to thank you.
威登酒吧
如果你非要到处跟着我
If you're going to have to follow me everywhere,
至少别躲着  好吗
at least don't lurk, all right?
我必须盯着你
I can't let you out of my sight.
你不喜欢去哪儿都见到我
You're sick of seeing me everywhere you go;
躲着似乎是个不错的折中办法
lurking seemed like a good compromise.
效果不太好啊
Yeah, well, it's not.
家人间和谐相处很难
Family's hard.
有时他们是世界上最难相处的
Sometimes they're the hardest in the world.
相亲相爱  团团圆圆
Loving someone so much and letting them love you back.
你说得对  你还是回去躲着比较好
You know, you're right... You should go back to lurking.
我经常跟你家人待在一起
I've spent a lot of time with your family.
如果这样你就觉得能插手我的事了
If you think that gives you the right to weigh in,
你就大错特错了
you're wrong.
再说了  奥利弗很快就成穷光蛋了
Plus, Oliver will be out of money soon
你也会失业的
and you'll be unemployed.
可不是
Right.
趁我失业前我得赶紧劝劝你
I guess I should get this in under the wire.
你妈妈并不完美
You know, your mother isn't perfect.
经常犯错
Her judgment definitely isn't.
但她唯一始终如一的就是
But there's one thing she's consistent about
她爱你和奥利弗
is that she loves you and Oliver.
那你觉得这应该为她赢得什么吗
And that should buy her what in your mind?
我不知道  西娅
Well, I don't know, Thea...
但她是你的母亲
But she is your mother.
总该有点儿分量吧
That should buy her something.
要不再给她次机会吧
A second chance, maybe.
全市通缉一名罪犯
...A citywide man hunt for the perpetrator of an attack
他造成一名警员重伤
that left one police officer seriously injured
一名警员死亡
and the other dead.
我们将播放旁观者录制的现场视频
We have video shot by a bystander,
但提醒某些观众
but please be warned that the
重大新闻
影像甚是清晰
footage may be too graphic for some viewers.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
西娅
Thea...
我要去见个朋友
I have to go see a friend.
如果你非要跟  那就跟吧
If you have to follow, follow.
这些可不会让你膝盖好起来
These aren't going to fix your knee.
它们会让膝盖好得快一点
They'll help it heal faster.
那痊愈之前呢
And until then?
面部识别有什么进展吗
Where are we with facial recognition?
交通摄像头拍得不清楚
Traffic cams can't get a clear shot.
现在我知道你戴兜帽的原因了
Now I see why you wear that hood.
无人匹配
费利西蒂  我们要先找到他
Felicity... We need to find Roy before the police do.
因为警察找到他后会杀了他  而我们不会吗
Because they'll kill him and we won't?
尖端科研实验室正在研究解药
S.T.A.R. Labs is working on a cure.
或许他们永远都研究不出来
Which they may never come up with.
即便有解药了  但在这期间
And even if they do, I mean, how many people
得会有多少人死在罗伊手上
are we going to let Roy kill in the meantime?
你本来也想杀了海伦娜
You know, you wanted to kill Helena, too.
但你找到别的方法了
You found another way.
这是两回事  你心知肚明
That was different, and you know it.
罗伊体内有米拉库鲁  跟斯莱德一样
Roy has the Mirakuru in him, just like Slade.
如果现在你有机会杀死斯莱德
And if you had a clear shot of Slade right now,
你一定会下手
you would take it.
罗伊不是斯莱德
Roy isn't Slade!
罗伊不是罗伊了
Roy isn't Roy.
他已经不是他自己了
He's not himself anymore,
无法挽救了
he's too far gone.
我不相信
I don't believe that.
你知道你在说些什么吗  奥利
Do you even hear yourself right now, Ollie?
五年前我们就有过一模一样的对话
This is the exact conversation that we had five years ago,
唯一不同是那时我们在炼狱岛上快冻死了
except we were freezing on Lian Yu.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
做该做的
What needs to be done.
一枪爆头  米拉库鲁也救不了他
The Mirakuru won't do anything against a head shot.
莎拉
Sara!
你母亲的集会半小时后就会开始
Your mother's rally starts in a half an hour.
我要是你就赶快开始打扮了
I'd start getting dressed if I were you.
她让我想起我刚回来的时候
She reminds me so much of me after I came home.
一切都看起来...
When it just seemed...
什么都不相信  甚至是希望
Seemed impossible to believe in anything even resembling hope.
但你相信了
But you did.
你相信了
You did.
最终还是相信了
Eventually.
莎拉也会的
Sara will, too.
谢谢你能来
Oh, thanks for coming.
今天很冷
It's chill.
那是谁
Who's that?
我
I...
我的影子
my shadow.
听着  罗伊有点儿不对劲
Listen, something is going on with Roy.
我知道  我见过他  他彻底疯了
I know, I saw him. He's totally crazed.
他到底怎么了
What's happening to him?
你还记得圣诞节他放我们鸽子那次吗
Do you remember around Christmas when he bailed on us?
怎么了
Yeah?
他被注射了一种药
He got shot up with something, this drug,
这种药让他神志不清
and it's been messing with his head.
你和我哥哥说过这件事吗
Did you tell my brother any of this?
没有  为什么这么问
No...why?
那是他派来盯着我的保镖
He's got this bodyguard all over me.
他肯定清楚罗伊的事
He must know about Roy,
以为罗伊是想找我还是什么
think he's coming after me or something.
你打算怎么办
Well, what are you going to do?
罗伊
Roy?
罗伊  是我
Roy, it's me.
我是西娅
It's Thea.
真高兴我找到你了
I'm so glad I found you.
我一直到处找你
I've been looking everywhere.
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
因为我你才变成这样
I did this to you.
你和我分手是因为你需要帮助
When you broke up with me, it was a cry for help,
可是我没有听你解释
and I didn't listen.
我真该受到惩罚
I should be punished.
我活该受到惩罚
I deserve to be punished.
如果别人伤害到你
Someone hurts you,
你就要伤害他们更深
and you hurt them worse.
要无休止地伤害他们
You hurt them permanently.
你应该杀了我
You should just kill me.
杀了我
Kill me.
奥利弗你去哪了  你接到我的电话了吗
Oliver, where have you been? Haven't you got any of my calls?
我刚才没时间  怎么了
I've been busy. What's wrong?
是你妈妈
It's your mother.
她会没事的
She'll do fine.
不  她不会
No, she won't.
这次活动不是为了集结大家
She's not using this event to rally the troops.
她是想利用这次机会
She's using it...
告诉大家她要退出竞选
to tell people she's dropping out of the race.
奥利弗
Oliver.
发生什么了
What happened?
摩托车事故
It's a motorcycle accident,
是我大意了
it was stupid.
没错  如果我算的没错
Yes, this would be the second accident in as many weeks,
这是几周以来的第二次事故了
if my math is correct.
马克说你要退出竞选
Mark says you're dropping out of the race.
其实我几个礼拜之前就该就这么做
The truth is, I should have done it weeks ago,
在西娅被绑架之后
after Thea was abducted.
我的全部心思应该放在修复我们的关系上
My complete focus needs to be on repairing our relationship.
妈妈  西娅现在的情形
Mom, what's happening with Thea right now
不是你没花时间陪她造成的
isn't because you weren't spending enough time with her.
也许不是吧  但是我必须做点儿什么
Well, maybe not. I have to do something
我不知道除了这个我还能做什么
and I'm not sure what else to do.
西娅恨你是因为你过去做的那些事
Thea hates you right now because of the things that you've done.
那些糟糕的事
Terrible things.
所以让她看到你做些好事
So let her see you do something good.
作为一位市长
As mayor.
妈妈  我了解一些事
Mom, I know a little something about...
例如为了这个城市
sacrificing the people closest to me
牺牲我身边最亲近的人
for the good of this city.
这就是你现在应该做的
It's what you need to do now.
我知道
I know.
很好
Good.
奥利弗  我知道
Oliver, I know.
我知道
I know.
我想
I've known...
从去年开始我就知道了
since last year, I suppose.
那个计划实施的那天
The night of the undertaking,
所有谜题都解开了
everything became so clear.
也是从那天开始我晚上再也睡不着
It was pretty much the night I stopped sleeping.
在你想说什么之前
Before you say anything else--
我不想说什么
There's nothing else to say.
我不需要说什么
Nothing I need to say.
除了告诉你我感到无比骄傲
Except I could not be more proud.
你要喝点什么吗
Can I have the raise get you anything to drink?
或者吃些东西  这边请
Or--or something to eat, perhaps? Please.
奥利弗在哪
Where's Oliver?
他去替我办事了
Ah, he's...running an errand for me.
刚好我们可以有机会聊一聊
I thought it would give us a chance to talk.
无意冒犯  奎恩夫人
With all due respect, um, Mrs. Queen,
这是我和奥利弗之间的事
what's happening, it's between me and your son.
当然了
Yes.
那是什么
What is that?
我的调查员给我的一份关于你的档案
Oh, I had one of our investigators write up a dossier on you.
抱歉  但是预防
I'm sorry, but it's a necessary
欺诈性亲权索赔是非常有必要的
precaution against a fraudulent claim of paternity.
孩子是奥利弗的
Well, the baby is Oliver's.
我对此毫不怀疑
Oh, of that I have no doubt.
我们的调查员调查得很全面
Our investigators were quite thorough.
但是你能想象到
But you can imagine
外面有多少人等着
how many people my family attracts
把我们家的事登上新闻
who are looking for handouts.
我不是为了钱
Well, I'm not looking for money.
当然不是
Of course not.
我说了我不想要钱
I told you, I don't want money.
那我告诉你
And I'm telling you
这是我第一次当奶奶
that this is my first grandchild.
我想要确保这个孩子有一个美好的未来
And I want to make certain that he or she has a bright future.
请收下吧
Please.
这有一百万
This is a million dollars.
我同样也希望我儿子有一个美好的未来
I want to make certain that my son has a bright future as well.
这一百万给你
That money is yours
前提是你告诉奥利弗孩子没了
once you tell Oliver that you've lost the baby.
你说什么
What?!
等你回中央城后再也不要联系他
And another million when you return to Central city,
我会再给你一百万
never to speak to him again.
我可以给你一个建议吗
Can I offer you some advice,
以一位母亲的身份告诫另一位母亲
one mother to another?
一旦事情涉及到你自己的孩子
When it comes to your children, there is no action
没有什么事情是你做不出来的
that is inconceivable;
也没有什么决定是你下不了的
there is no decision that is impossible.
你会奋不顾身给他他所需要的生活
You do what you must to provide the life that they need.
所以我认为那二百万美元
And I think that $2 million
可以给我们的孩子提供他们所需要的生活
is sufficient to provide the life that both our children need.
你觉得呢
Don't you?
支持奎恩竞选市长
当我最初决定参加此次竞选时
When I was first approached about entering this race,
我觉得竞选成功的机会是如此渺茫
the prospect of winning seemed a distant,
是几乎不可能的事
nearly impossible feat.
一个遭受重创的城市
Now, how could a city that had suffered so much
怎么可能寄希望于给它带来创伤的人
place its faith in someone so responsible for its suffering?
但是这几个星期以来
But as the weeks progressed,
那些如你们一样正直的人
good people such as you
表明了你们的态度
raised your voices
支持我  于是我想我可以让这座城市更美好
in support, and I began to think that I could make a difference.
我可以为拯救这座城市出一份力
I could help save this city.
莫伊拉·奎恩支持者聚会
但
But...
最近发生的一些事改变了这一切
recent events have changed things, and...
不过现在我确信我可以让这座城市更美好
and now I know I can make a difference.
如果我能有幸当选市长
And should the honor become mine,
我郑重地向各位保证
I promise with every breath I take
莫伊拉·奎恩支持者聚会
为了这座城市的美好未来
To do what is necessary,
我将不惜一切代价  不顾一切牺牲
To sacrifice what is necessary for the good of this city.
星城是我的家  你们都是我的家人
Starling City is my home, you are my family,
对我来说没有什么比家人更重要
And there is nothing more important to me than family.
谢谢大家
Thank you, thank you all.
说得太好了  莫伊拉
Great speech, Moira.
虽然跟我中意的相差有些远
A little too off-book for my liking,
但我们会努力的
But we'll work on that.
我觉得很好
I thought it was perfect.
我想上来说几句
I just wanted to come up here and say a few words.
今晚我很高兴我母亲能来
I am so proud to have my mom here tonight
我这间贫民区的威登酒吧
at my club, Verdant, in the Glades.
她在干什么
What is she doing?
她知道这是直播
She knows this is being televised.
她这是想引罗伊出来
She's sending a message to Roy, trying to draw him out.
请为奎恩投票  跟你们的朋友也这么说
So vote Queen. Tell your friends.
谢谢
Thanks.
西娅
Thea.
我不是为了你
That was not for you.
天呐  你真沉
Oh, God, you're heavy.
真的都是肌肉的重量吗
Is this really all muscle?
我们还有多少支毒箭
How many of those venom arrows do we have?
-大约20支  -我全都要带上
- About 20. - I need all of them.
好吧  你确定这样做好吗
Okay. Are you sure that's a good idea?
你膝盖现在这样还能穿上战袍吗
Can you even get into those leather pants with that knee?
马上给我利多卡因
Lidocaine. Now.
一种局部麻醉剂
我看一下  上面写着合适的剂量是
Let's see, the bottle says the proper dose is...
全部
Is all of it.
我觉得这样不...
I don't think that's a good...
说得太棒了  莫伊拉
Terrific speech, Moira.
我们几年前就应该推选你
How did we not think of running you years ago?
谢谢
Thank you.
我能失陪一会吗
Can you give me a moment?
当然
Of course.
你好
Oh, hello.
-你得离开了  -不不不
- You need to go now! - No, no, no!
我不能丢下我女儿
I can't leave without my daughter!
我会保护好你女儿的
I'll see to the safety of your daughter!
走  西娅  我们得离开了
Go, go! Thea, we have to go now!
不  是罗伊
No, it's Roy!
我不会离开他  他为我而来
I'm not leaving him! He came here for me!
罗伊
Roy.
罗伊  听我说
Roy, listen to me!
好好听我说
Listen to my voice!
我不知道你是怎么了
I don't know what's going on with you,
但我坚信我深爱的那个人
but I have to believe the man I fell in love with
他还活着
is still inside there, somewhere.
你要反抗  你很坚强
You have to fight. You're strong.
你能反抗的  你要反抗
You can fight this. Fight this!
罗伊
Roy!
把她放下
Put her down.
不要杀他
Please don't..
他也控制不了
he can't control it.
所以我也没有办法
That's why I don't have a choice.
闪开
Get out of the way.
别这样
Don't do this.
杀了我
Kill me.
求你了
Please.
杀了我
Kill me.
千万不要杀他
Please don't do it!
今晚谁都不会死
No one dies tonight.
但是警察会...
But he police...
出去
Go outside.
我们会帮助罗伊
We'll get Roy the help he needs.
我保证  快走
I promise! Go!
西藏蝮蛇毒
Tibetan pit viper venom.
常用剂量对他来说没用  对吧
A constant dose of that can't be good for you. Right?
他会像当初斯莱德那样昏迷
It'll keep him sedated like it did Slade.
昏迷到什么时候
Until when?
我们要是用完毒剂了怎么办
And what happens when we run out?
这又不是非处方药
It's not like you can buy this stuff over the counter.
要是在西藏的话  可能可以买到
Unless you're in Tibet. Then...maybe.
我们要照顾好他
We'll take care of him.
我不想放弃罗伊
I'm not ready to give up on Roy.
大战一场之后有谁想吃点东西吗
Anyone else crave dim sum after fisticuffs?
都不吃  好吧
No? Ok.
那我就把饺子都吃了
Dumplings for one, then.
我本来要杀他的
I would have killed him.
我已经准备好了
I was ready to.
如果不是你拦着  他现在已经死了
He'd be dead right now if you wouldn't have stopped me.
可他现在没死
But he's not.
这才是关键
That's all that matters.
你说的不对
That's not true.
我想杀死他
I wanted to kill roy.
因为这才是我该做的
Because that's what I do.
这才是我的本性
That's who I am.
我在炼狱中生活了六年
I spent six years in the darkness.
我看着恶魔的双眼
And I looked into the eyes of the devil
把我的灵魂交给了他
and I gave him my soul.
让我帮你找回你的灵魂
Let me help you get it back.
不  你应该找个更好的人
No, you deserve someone better.
能够理解你内心深处的人
Someone who can harness that light that's still inside of you.
但那个人不是我
But I'm not that person.
永远都不会是我
And I never will be.
莎拉
Sara...
不要
Don't.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我太在乎你了  所以不能跟你在一起
I just care about you too much to be with you.
一切都还好吗
Everything OK?
是的  只是这一天太不顺了
Yeah. Just had a long day.
罗伊怎么样了
How's Roy?
他还活着
Well, he's alive,
不用谢我
No thanks to me.
你敢挡在我面前真的很勇敢
You know, that was brave getting between us.
-这需要很大的勇气  -也未必
- It took guts. - Not really.
我知道你不是真想伤害他
I knew you wouldn't really hurt him.
你不是杀手
You're not a killer.
这是什么意思
What's this for?
告别
Say good-bye.
什么  等一下  你要去哪
What? Wait, where are you going?
去见个老朋友
To see an old friend.
这座城市所有的警察都出动了
We've got every cop in this city canvassing.
-我们会找到这个人的  -谢谢
- We'll find this guy. - Thank you.
你还好吗
You OK?
还行
Fine.
你去哪了
Where were you?
跟我在一起
He was with me.
你们俩和好真是太好了
Glad to see the two of you are getting along again.
西娅
Thea...
罗伊的事你早就知道
You knew about Roy.
什么
What?
所以你才让你的保镖跟踪我
That's why you had your bodyguard stalking me.
你知道他到底是怎么回事
Somehow, you knew what was going on with him.
我是想保护你
I'm just trying to protect you.
通过不告诉我真相来保护我吗
By not telling me the truth.
就跟马尔科姆·梅林的事一样
Just like with Malcolm Merlyn.
知道吗  你们两个
You know, the two of you,
你们以为有事瞒着我  跟我说谎
you think you're protecting me by lying
就是保护我
and by keeping secrets.
但其实那样才最伤害我
But that's what's actually hurting me.
你说得很对
You're absolutely right.
我们需要走出过去重新开始
We need to turn a new page.
没那么简单
It's not going to be that simple.
也没那么容易
Or easy.
我知道  如果真相于我而言容易的话
I know. If the truth were easy for me,
我们就不会陷入现在这种境地了
we wouldn't be in this situation.
但首先
But to start...
你和奥利弗都需要知道一件
there's something about Malcolm that both you and Oliver
关于马尔科姆的事
need to know.
马尔科姆...
Malcolm...
奥利弗
Oliver!
我得死
I need to die.
奥利弗
Oliver!
上次你让我选择的时候
I was dead the last time
我选择了死亡
you were offered this choice.
斯莱德
Slade...
奥利弗
Oliver...
这是怎么回事
What's happening?
我一直想知道...
I often wonder how you looked...
他用枪指着莎朵把她从我身边夺走时
when he pointed the gun at Shado...
你是什么表情
and took her from me.
你个变态
You psychopath.
莎朵  莎朵不是你的
Shado...Shado wasn't yours!
对  她曾经是你的
No, she was yours.
可是后来你选了别的女人没选她
Until you chose another woman over her.
不是这样的
That's not what happened!
就是这样  就是
It is what happened! It is!
她告诉我的
She told me!
你说她是什么意思  那里根本没人
What do you mean, she? There's nobody there!
斯莱德
Slade...
当时你也跟奥利弗一起在岛上吗
You were on the island with Oliver?
我开始以为自己知道什么是真正的绝望
I thought I had known true despair,
直到后来遇到了你儿子
until I met your son.
我信任他...
I trusted him...
会做出正确的选择
to make the right choice.
现在让我做出正确的选择吧
Let me make the right choice now.
杀我吧
Kill me.
-不  -不要
- NO! - NO!
杀我吧  求你了
Choose me, please!
我会杀你的  奥利弗
I am killing you, Oliver.
不过不会先杀你
Only more slowly than you would like.
不要
Don't.
选吧
Choose.
-不要  -选吧
- Don't-- - Choose.
求你了
Please...
快选
Choose!
我对天发誓  我一定会杀了你
I swear to God, I am going to kill you!
不  不要
No! No!
不
No.
妈...
Mom...
不
No!
妈  你干什么
Mom, what are you doing?
要结束今晚
There's only one way
-只有一个办法  -不要
- this night can end. - No!
求你了  不要
Please don't.
我们都知道是什么办法
And we both know that.
是不是  威尔逊先生
Don't we, Mr. Wilson?
妈  求你了  不要
Mom! Please, don't!
不要杀我的孩子
Both my children will live.
妈
Mom!
你干什么
What are you doing?!
妈
Mom!
西娅  我爱你
Thea, I love you.
闭上眼睛  孩子
Close your eyes, baby!
不要
No!
你拥有真正的勇气
You possess true courage.
真的很抱歉
I am truly sorry...
什么
What?
可是你的勇气没有
You did not pass that on
传给你儿子
to your son.
不
No!
这件事结束之前
There is still one person
还有一个人
who has to die...
必须得死
before this can end.
不要
No!
妈
Mom?
妈  不
Mom! No!
不  妈
No! Mom!
对  我也很抱歉
Well, yeah, I'm sorry, too.
如果有什么我可以帮忙的话...
Well, listen, if there's ever anything that I can do--
喂
Hello?
是谁
Who was that?
是...
That was, um...
她失去了孩子
She lost the baby.
她说自己很伤心
She said she's sad about it,
要回中心区的学校去了
and she's going to go back to school in central city.
她在那边肯定有家人
Apparently she has family there.
她肯定很痛苦
Well, I'm sure this has been very traumatic for her.
但这样对她也许是最好的
But it sounds for the best.
-是啊  -你没事吧
- Sure. - You OK?
没事  没事
Yeah. Yes.
我仍然是世界上最幸运的人
I continue to be the luckiest guy on the planet.
要是...
What...
我该怎么办啊  要是...
What would I have done if she...
我还没做好当爸爸的准备
I'm not ready to be a dad.
现在没有  但总有一天会的
No. But someday.
这是我最大的希望
It's my fondest hope for you.
我很高兴我告诉你了
I'm glad I told you.
要是你不在我身边
I don't think that I could have
我一个人肯定不知道怎么办
gotten through something like this without you.
我会一直在你身边的
You're never without me.
我的乖儿子
My beautiful boy.
妈...
It's, uh...
我爱你
I love you.